

Android Developer



I am currently 100% involved in Android development. I started as a Java developer and for 6 years I learned a lot about Java and Javascript, but discovering the Android world was a big positive change for me. Since then I try to improve my developer skills. Now I am developing with Kotlin and I try to follow the SOLID principles of programming. I like technical work and I enjoy learning new things.

In my spare time I like besides stay with my family or reading or practice sport, playing with the IoT and the 3D printing although in a very amateur way.

Tech skills —

Android Framework

Kotlin / Java

SOLID / Clean Architecture

MVVM / MVP / DI / Testina

Jenkins / Sonar

Git. GitHub

More tech skills —

Android Jetpack Firebase

Design patterns

Postman

Javascript

Regex

Tinkercad, Arduino, Raspberry Pi 3D printing

Other skills ——

Agile methodologies

JIRA and Confluence

Employment

Currently

Jeff | Valencia

Android Developer

In Jeff Company I started as the only developer of the legacy code of the app. We are currently three developers. Our day-to-day work is to develop the product while refactoring the code and reduce a large technical debt. We try to follow the SOLID principles, do tests and a bit of pair programming. We have based the technology on the tools provided by Jetpack: MVVM, Room and Data binding. We also use DI. Kotlin is our leguage and we also take advantage of the benefits of Jenkins for the part of Cl and CD when distributing the betas and together with Sonar we monitor the software quality.

2016 - 2018

Develapps | Valencia

Android Developer

At Develapps I work in small and medium Android projects with Java and Kotlin, using the last tecnologies of continuous integration and also design patterns, UI and Unit testing, RRSS integration, pay platforms, etc. with agile methodologies. These are some of the clients for whom I have worked: Hofmann, Fermax, Ingénico, Porcelanosa.

2010 - 2016

Capgemini | Valencia

J2E Developer

I've been working in J2E development using lastest technologies and frameworks like Java, Spring, Hibernate, Devon Framework, Sencha ExtJS, jQuery, HTML5 and CSS3. Making high quality code with continuous integration with Jenkins, Sonar Qube, unit testing and also Scrum as an Agile framework for complete with success the big projects. I've been developing for important customers like Universidad de Valencia,

Aguas de Valencia, Ayuntamiento de Valencia and Sanidad.

2004 - 2006

Asoin 21 | Valencia

Desktop Apps Developer

I worked as a desktop applications programmer, developing with Visual Basic, Sql Server, GeneXus, GXplorer and Crystal Reports.

I've participated in large part of the most important company projects:

- Quorum ERP for integrated management of entreprises.
- And a GXplorer datawarehouse project for Inlet Sealsh Corp.

Education

2005-2007 I.E.S Blasco Ibáñez | Valencia
 Degree for Technical Specialist Electronic Product Development
 2002-2004 I.E.S Serpis | Valencia

Degree for Technical Specialist Application Development.

Certificates

Architect CODERS | By antonioleyva.com

Kotlin para desarrolladores Android | By antonioleyva.com
70-480: Programming in HTML5
with JavaScript and CSS3 | By Microsoft

Android Application Developer | By ATC

FCE (English B2 Level) | By British Council

SCJP SE6 (Java 6) | By Sun Microsystems

Languages

Spanish | Native

Contact



+034 669 287 256



davidasensio81@gmail.com

